Ganesh AlalaSundaram

A Dev-Test Professional with 8+ Yrs of exp looking for SDET Lead/SDET/Scrum Master/Program Manager roles.

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, Tamil Nadu - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Ganesh-AlalaSundaram/dd5b500021e61f65

My long-term career objective is to lead programs that solves complex problems, responsible

for product delivery and building products that positively impacts millions of consumers and enterprise users.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

WORK EXPERIENCE

Consultant SDET

Microsoft -

June 2013 to Present

June 2013 - Present)

Product Technologies: Cloud & amp; Mobile Migrations, DevOps for Test Strategies, Visual Studio,

- \bullet Orchestrated projects as an Individual Contributor and Led teams across global engagements.
- \bullet Contributed to 60% of the software component automation in the projects. Streamlined process

and tools for Dev-Ops implementation that included training, metrics and reporting.

 ullet Led Manual and Automated Test Management to elevate the quality of Mobile (x Platform),

Cloud and IoT Applications. Designed, Developed and Maintained automation coverage for UI

and API layer by handshaking Visual Studio with Open Source frameworks.

 ${\boldsymbol \cdot}$ Migrated millions of customers to Azure Cloud through FastTrack program. Developed Tools that

reduced manual efforts worth 40 hours for each process.

Programmer Analyst

Cognizant -

March 2010 to May 2013

Built WCF services for iOS and Android Applications for a PoC which helped business to grab more mobile projects.

• Delivered quality of products to customers with the stipulated time. Stand-ups, defect triage,

brown bag sessions, bug-bash and retrospectives. Owned and managed weekly quality report.

 $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Initiated transformation of web to mobile apps within project and assisted senior stakeholders

of the company in analyzing the opportunity.

Projects

IoT and Smart City Projects

 \bullet Formulated the use of VSO Dashboards for ease of status reporting which reduced manual

effort of an hour per day.

https://www.indeed.com/r/Ganesh-AlalaSundaram/dd5b500021e61f65?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

https://www.indeed.com/r/Ganesh-AlalaSundaram/dd5b500021e61f65?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

 \bullet Leveraged developer background to automate UI and API components through C#, Xamarin

UI in iOS and Android apps.

• Led process improvements that standardized operations that included on-boarding/reporting and customer acceptance.

PubSec Projects - Dubai/Columbia/New York

- Coordinated between in-house and client teams and kept stakeholders informed of progress and milestones.
- ${\mbox{\tiny \bullet}}$ Supervised an avg. of 10-member software QA team in developing and implementing quality-

assurance and quality-control methodologies to ensure compliance with ${\tt QA}$ standards.

- Created tools that helped the development ecosystem by automating the long running manual process.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Brought a strong focus on "voice of the customer" into the software development function to

ensure product and customer success

Portfolio

MSDN Blog - https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/ganesh/ GitHub Repo- https://github.com/ganesh-alalasundaram/ Personal Website: http://www.ganeshalalasundaram.com

EDUCATION

Software Product Management

Product School - New York, NY

Bachelor of Computer Science in Computer Science Engineering

Anna University

SKILLS

Automation, Testing, Mobile Testing, SDET, Scrum Master

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)

PUBLICATIONS

MSDN

https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/ganesh

GIT

https://github.com/ganesh-alalasundaram

https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/ganesh https://github.com/ganesh-alalasundaram